Thomas Waldick

Front-End Software Engineer

Address: Raumerstraße 29, 10437,

Berlin

Email: contact@thomaswaldick.com
Nationality: Deutsch / American
Website: thomaswaldick.com

Phone: +49 152 02589949 **LinkedIn:** <u>linkedin.com/in/</u>

thomas-waldick/ **Github**: github.com/
Thomaswaldick



Professional Profile

Front-End Developer with 7 years of experience specialized in **Javascript**. Developed a responsive web application in a dynamic startup environment, focusing on user interface design, cross-browser compatibility, and performance optimization.

Eager to bring my experience in front-end Javascript frameworks and dynamic work environments to your company, and contribute to its missions.

Primary stack: Vue.js, Typescript, Next.js, React.js, React Native, NoSQL (Firestore)

Work History

06/2018 - Present

Lead Software Engineer

Weight Room Coach - weightroomcoach.com | Chillicothe, USA (Remote) Software for schools to create wellness programs and strength training for coaches, athletes, administrators, and staff.

Tech stack: Vue.js, React Native, Nuxt.js, Firebase, Heroku

- Engineered a system from the ground up supporting ~4000 athletes using Cypress E2E testing and modular code.
- Scaled customer base from 0 to 38 school districts by developing a new Vue.js website and React Native mobile app.
- Measured a 200% increase in student-athletes metrics through customized workouts and programs.
- Established an Agile workflow using Github Actions, Trello, and Heroku.

05/2019 - 08/2019

Software Engineering Intern

Quicken Loans - quickenloans.com | Detroit, USA An online mortgage lender, offering home loans and refinancing solutions. **Tech stack**: .NET, C#, Angular, AWS, SQL

- Developed custom internal AWS developer tools using Angular.
- Resolved tech issues on the Quicken Loans Mortgage System Support Team through a SAFe workflow.
- Eliminated numerous bugs in an existing code base using .NET and C#.

05/2018 - 12/2018

Student Software Engineer

Ohio University - ohio.edu | Athens, USA

The Office of Information Technology creates software for the university.

Tech stack: Angular, Ansible, Groovy, Grails, Java, NodeJS

- Automated CI/CD processes using languages like Ansible and Groovy.
- Engineered website features for students and faculty through Angular and Grails.
- Participated in an Agile work environment to complete code sprints using tools including Jira and Bamboo.

Education

08/2017 - 05/2021

Bachelor of Science in **Computer Science**

Ohio University Athens, Ohio, USA

Additional Skills & Interests

Languages

• English (Native), German (A1.1)

Skills

- Advanced Knowledge: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Vue.js
- Intermediate: C#, C++, Next.js, Python, React.js, React Native, TypeScript
- Basic: .NET, Ansible, Angular, AWS, Groovy, Grails, Java, jQuery, Lua, SQL

Interests

- I love playing board games to connect with friends and unwind offline.
- I enjoy watching Youtube videos and Twitch streamers while working on coding side projects.